Sanjar Adilov | Curriculum Vitae

■ sshadylov@gmail.com • \$\pi\$ sanjaradylov.github.io • \$\pi\$ sanjaradylov in sanjaradylov

ML Software Engineer, BSc in Applied Math and Computer Science. Broadly interested in machine learning, esp. deep learning and its applications in natural language processing. Working on full-stack research and development of conversational AI experiences.

Employment

Data Scientist Aug 2022 - Present Alif Tech Tashkent. Uzbekistan

Modeling, development & operationalization of a task-oriented, closed-domain conversational AI assistant.

Little bit of backend and/or modeling for document OCR, credit scoring, transaction fraud monitoring.

Research Engineer II

Jan 2021 - Aug 2022

Romanovsky Institute of Mathematics, Academy of Sciences of Uzbekistan

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

Adapting deep learning for drug design by building a unified framework for downstream generative and supervised molecular tasks via large-scale causal transformers (see, e.g., smiles-gpt).

Research Assistant Jan 2019 - Dec 2020

Romanovsky Institute of Mathematics, Academy of Sciences of Uzbekistan

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

- Single-/multi-output classification of high-dimensional molecular data (see, e.g., sparse-cheml).
- Improvement of SOTA generative molecular models (see, e.g., moleculegen).
- Survival analysis of patients with COVID-19 in Uzbekistan.

Research Engineer I

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

Romanovsky Institute of Mathematics, Academy of Sciences of Uzbekistan

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

ML for low-data QSPR/QSAR modeling using graph neural networks (see, e.g., nitrocom-learning).

Intern Jun 2017 - Aug 2018 Misc. Tashkent, Uzbekistan

Several internships. Mostly bash scripting and basic frontend & backend development.

Skills

- Programming Languages: Python &, Bash, SQL, LaTeX, C, R.
- Tools: [DS] PyTorch 4, @ Transformers & co., Keras, Scikit-Learn & co., XGBoost β, Pandas, etc.; [MLE] DVC, MLFlow, Label Studio; [SE] Git, Sanic, Docker, K8S, Django, FastAPI.
- Concepts & Practices: Scientific Research, CI/CD, Scrum, OSSD.

Education

BSc in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science

Sep 2014 - Jun 2018

Lomonosov Moscow State University in Tashkent

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

- Main coursework include pure & applied math, intelligent systems, and scientific computing.
- Research and thesis on graph theory (coloring and planarity testing).
- Volunteer instructor at Math and Programming Club for prospective students.
- ACM-ICPC NEERC contestant.

Miscellaneous

- Publications: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=NzU11nAAAAAJ
- Community Service: Mentoring in hackathons (one has eventually become an integral part of our credit scoring ecosystem); public presentations on DL life cycle, foundational models.
- Side Projects: scikit-fallback: machine learning w/ rejections (on Medium and Github).
- **Hobbies**: Guitars, music, books, movies, swimming.
- Languages: Uzbek (native), Russian (full proficiency), English (TOEFL 108/120, 2024).